{"tossups": [{"question": "Nick Gnedin\u2019s CROC code tracks how this property is acquired through cosmic time. This property for the universe is often measured in terms of the redshift and optical depth at which it happens. A prefactor of the inverse cube of the deBroglie (\u201cduh-broy\u201d) wavelength times the ratio of two degeneracies of state multiplies a Boltzmann factor in one equation for the degree of this property. \u201cThe cube root of three fourths pi times flux over number density squared over the rate of the inverse of this process\u201d is the radius of a region produced by O and B stars which fully possesses this property, the (*) Stromgren sphere.  The Langmuir-Saha equation is used to assess the degree of this property within stars. H-II (\u201cH-two\u201d) regions are defined by fully possessing this property. The \u201cdark ages\u201d end when the universe began possessing this property, since before then, electrons could absorb photons and prevent their transmission. For 10 points, name this property of an atom which has lost an electron. ", "answer": "reionization [accept word forms like ionized]", "subcategory": "Astronomy", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "Meisner et al used a sulfide group and a carbon-carbon pi bond to form a one-molecule example of these devices. A digital type of these devices, also called resistive digital-to-analog converters, are used to trim analog signals. Soft membrane examples of these things can be activated by touch. \u201cString\u201d examples of these things are used to measure position and velocity and are often \u201cmulti-turn.\u201d These devices are used to provide position feedback to motors in a (*) servo (\u201cSUR-voh\u201d) mechanism. These adjustable devices feature a wiper changing a contact point by moving along a long linear groove or an arc. Using only two terminals of these devices creates a rheostat. In circuit diagrams, the symbol for these elements are resistor symbols with arrows. For 10 points, name these three-terminal circuit elements often used to make voltage dividers, whose variable resistance can be adjusted by turning a knob. ", "answer": "potentiometer", "subcategory": "Physics", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "An enzyme called BASU that quickly transfers this molecule is fused to the Lambda-N aptamer binding domain for use in the RaPID procedure. \u201cPainting\u201d with this molecule preferentially targets intrinsically disordered regions. A phenol-containing derivative of this molecule is the substrate for the evolved peroxidase APEX\u00b72. 2-imino and desthio- derivatives of this molecule obviate the need for harsh conditions. BioID and TurboID transfer this molecule promiscuously in proximity labelling. The displacement of the dye H\u00b7A\u00b7B\u00b7A is used to measure its concentration. This molecule contains a valeric (\u201cvuh-LAIR-ick\u201d) acid side chain attached to a bicyclic (*) thiophene-ureido (\u201cTHIGH-oh-feen-u-RYE-doh\u201d) moiety. A 15-amino acid recognition sequence for Bir\u00b7A, called the AviTag, attaches to this molecule, which is a cofactor in several carboxylase enzymes. For 10 points, name this molecule whose non-covalent interaction with streptavidin (\u201cstrep-TAV-id-in\u201d) is very strong.", "answer": "biotin [or vitamin B7; or vitamin H]", "subcategory": "Chemistry", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "A structural protein in this virus has Y\u00b793\u00b7H and L\u00b731\u00b7V resistance mutations. The Huh\u00b77 cell line is often used to grow this virus, whose replication requires the micro\u00b7R\u00b7N\u00b7A m\u00b7i\u00b7R-122. Antibodies that neutralize this virus often bind to its E\u00b72 envelope glycoprotein. Up to 50% of patients with porphyria (\u201cpore-FEAR-ee-uh\u201d) cutanea (\u201ckew-TAYN-ee-uh\u201d) tarda (\u201cTARD-uh\u201d) are infected with this virus, infection with which is also associated with Type II mixed cryoglobulinemia (\u201cCRY-oh-glob-yew-lin-NEE-mee-uh\u201d). Several drugs targeting this virus bind to its N\u00b7S\u00b75\u00b7A and N\u00b7S\u00b75\u00b7B non\u00b7structural proteins. All six genotypes of this virus are targeted by the combination of (*) so\u00b7fos\u00b7bu\u00b7vir and vel\u00b7pat\u00b7as\u00b7vir. A secondary structure formed by this virus\u2019 genome binds directly to the 40\u00b7S ribosomal subunit, bypassing the need for a cap; that it is internal ribosome entry site. This virus is commonly transmitted through injection drugs and sex work, and usually causes a chronic infection. For 10 points, name this flavivirus (\u201cFLAHV-ee-virus\u201d) that infects the liver.", "answer": "Hepatitis C [or Hep C or HCV; prompt on hepatitis or hepatitis virus]", "subcategory": "Biology", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "Ishwaran and Lauer developed a random forest method for this kind of analysis, which uses the Nelson-Aalen method of estimating one parameter. One model used in this kind of analysis uses Breslow\u2019s method to resolve ties and assumes that covariates have a multiplicative effect on a function symbolized lambda sub zero. Prentice\u2019s generalized Wilcoxon test or a log-rank version of the Mantel-Haenszel test is used to compare samples in this kind of analysis. In this kind of analysis, the product of 1 minus d sub I over n sub I is an estimator of a function S of t; that estimator is named for Kaplan and Meier. Cox names a proportional (*) hazards model used in this analysis, whose data is often right-censored due to withdrawal or avoiding events. This kind of analysis is used to compare mortality rates in clinical trials by calculating a hazard ratio. For 10 points, name this method which models the duration until a particular event.", "answer": "survival analysis [or time-to-event analysis, or lifetime analysis, or failure time analysis, or TTE analysis, or reliability analysis, or duration analysis, or event history analysis accept Cox proportional hazards model until \u201chazards\u201d; accept \u201cmodelling\u201d instead of \u201canalysis\u201d]", "subcategory": "Math", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "Rayachauduri\u2019s equation for the time derivative of expansion contains a term equal to 2 times the shear squared minus 2 times a quantity representing this property squared. The size of an object with this property is modified by a prefactor of \u201c1 plus the square root of 1 minus a squared\u201d where \u2018a\u2019 is a parametrization of this quantity. The unusual existence of Killing [emphasize] tensors for systems with this property leads to the existence of (*) Carter\u2019s constant in systems with this property. Magnetic field squared times radius to the fourth times a measure of this property squared divided by the speed of light gives the power radiated by the Blandford-Znajek (\u201czuh-NYE-eck\u201d) process which can only occur in objects with this property. Metrics with this property often possess an ergosphere between the \u201cinner\u201d and \u201couter\u201d event horizons, and can stretch spacetime in the process of frame dragging. For 10 points, name this property possessed by a Kerr (\u201ccare\u201d) black hole.", "answer": "rotation or rotating [accept common-language equivalents, accept things like nonzero angular momentum]", "subcategory": "Physics", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "A solution of this compound is required to stain amyloid A\u00b7A, which doesn\u2019t stain with Congo Red. It\u2019s not the hydroxyl radical or DNAse I, but single-stranded DNA can be footprinted using this compound. A solution of this compound, K\u00b72\u00b7C\u00b7O\u00b73, and N\u00b7a\u00b7O\u00b7H is used to stain T\u00b7L\u00b7C plates when the analyte contains olefins. This compound is used to measure the kappa number, or lignin content, of wood pulp. 18-crown-6 is used to help dissolve this substance in benzene to create purple benzene. It\u2019s not ozone, but an acidic solution of this compound cleaves alkenes (\u201cAL-keenz\u201d) to carboxylic acids. Sodium oxalate is used to standardize a (*) solution of this compound in a common redox titration. When added to an alkene or alkyne (\u201cAL-kine\u201d), a solution of this compound evolves a brown precipitate in Baeyer\u2019s test for unsaturation. For 10 points, name this oxidizing agent whose metal atom has an oxidation state of 7, with formula KMnO4.", "answer": "potassium permanganate [accept KMnO4 before mention] ", "subcategory": "Chemistry", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "This substance is inactivated via phosphorylation (\u201cfos-FOR-il-ay-shun\u201d) to create its 22-phosphate. Crypto\u00b7cephal is a trans\u00b7activator of this substance\u2019s receptor, which is agonized by tebufenozide (\u201cte-bew-FEN-oh zide\u201d). Genes called Spook, Shadow, Disembodied, Phantom, and Shade all code for enzymes in the biosynthesis of this substance from keto\u00b7diol. P\u00b7T\u00b7T\u00b7H triggers the release of this substance from the ring gland. The receptor for this substance forms a hetero\u00b7dimer with the R\u00b7X\u00b7R-homolog ultra\u00b7spiracle for signaling. This substance triggers the formation of Balbiani (\u201cBAL-bee-AHN-ee\u201d) rings and puffs on salivary (*) polytene chromosomes. This hormone triggers the formation of exuviae (\u201cecks-SU-vee-ae\u201d), and is often required for complete metamorphosis. For 10 points, name this insect hormone that triggers molting.", "answer": "20-hydroxyecdysone [or 2-deoxyecdysone or ecdysterone or 20E]", "subcategory": "Biology", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "In the Ising (\u201cICE-ing\u201d) model, this quantity multiplies a Hamiltonian function of configuration in the expression for the configuration probability. It\u2019s not length, but Rudolf Peierls (\u201cPIE-earls\u201d) showed that for large values of this quantity, magnetization remains near negative one. In the grand canonical ensemble, absolute activity is equal to the exponential of this quantity times chemical potential. An expression for this quantity consisting of a single differential is derived by maximizing the number of (*) microstates at equilibrium to show that this quantity is equal for two systems at that point. The canonical partition function is equal to the sum over microstates of the exponential of negative this quantity times energy. This quantity equals the derivative of the natural log of number of microstates with respect to energy. For 10 points, name this quantity equal to the reciprocal of Boltzmann\u2019s constant times temperature.", "answer": "thermodynamic beta [accept one over Boltzmann\u2019s constant times temperature before mention]", "subcategory": "Physics", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "The two branches of K-theory can be related using the equivalence of two of these structures provided by the Serre-Swan theorem. If one of these structures S is locally small, then maps from S correspond to transformations of the map taking elements of S to their Hom-set. Natural transformations act on maps between these objects. One of these structures is \u201ctotal\u201d if its natural embedding into Set has a left adjoint. The group-theoretic Cayley\u2019s theorem generalizes to these structures via the (*) Yoneda (\u201cyoh-nay-duh\u201d) lemma. Depending on whether they preserve the direction of morphisms, maps between them are called covariant or contravariant functors. Diagrams of these structures commute if different paths give the same morphism. One of these structures is defined by taking monoids and their homomorphisms to objects and arrows. For 10 points, name these structures whose namesake theory is often called \u201cabstract nonsense\u201d because they generalize much of mathematics.", "answer": "categories [accept category theory]", "subcategory": "Math", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "Solving the hidden subgroup problem for the direct product of Z sub n with itself is equivalent to solving this problem. When solving this problem, the prime degree p of the finite field must be chosen so that p minus 1 is B-smooth for a large B. A factor base is used to search for a set of random relations that are solved as linear systems in the index calculus methods for solving this problem. For a primitive member of a field a, a message m, and two random integers x and y, ciphertext whose first member is a to the y and whose second member is a to the xy (\u201cx-y\u201d) is used in an (*) encryption scheme that relies on the difficulty of solving this problem. It\u2019s not factoring, but the hardness of this problem ensures the security of the ElGamal (\u201cel guh-MAHL\u201d), Diffie-Hellman, and other public-key encryption schemes. The solution to this problem is an integer x such that b equals a to the x. For 10 points name this problem, which involves calculating the inverse of discrete exponentiation.", "answer": "discrete logarithm problem [accept discrete logarithm]", "subcategory": "Computer Science", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "Compounds with this property reactively prefer even-numbered polyenes, cyclic polyenes, and even-hapticity polyenes by the Green-Davies-Mingos rules. The fact that hydroperoxide has more of this property than hydroxide is evidence of the alpha effect, in which proximity of species with this property increases it. Edwards and Ritchie\u2019s correlation are the basis for the oxibase scale of this property. A quantity measuring this property multiplies susceptibility in the extended Grunwald-Winstein equation and a substrate constant in the Swain-Scott equation. When adding to an arene (\u201cAIR-een\u201d), a compound with this property can form a Meisenheimer complex. The Kolbe synthesis has multiple products because the (*) cyanide anion can act as an ambident compound with this property. Compounds with this property induce inversion of configuration via backside attack in S\u00b7N\u00b72 reactions. For 10 points, name this property that lets compounds react with electrophiles.", "answer": "nucleophilicity [accept word forms of nucleophile; accept word forms of electrophile or electrophilicity before \u201cMeisenheimer\u201d, because some of the clues before that apply to both, but the clues after that all only apply to nucleophiles]", "subcategory": "Chemistry", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "Molecular subtypes of this disease include Luminal A and Luminal B. The C\u00b7D\u00b7K\u00b74 and C\u00b7D\u00b7K\u00b76 inhibitor ribociclib (\u201cree-BO-sick-lib\u201d) is approved to treat this disease. M\u00b7C\u00b7F\u00b77 cells are primarily used to study this disease. One drug used to treat this disease induces downregulation of neuregulin-1 (\u201cnew-REG-yew-lin-one\u201d) in cardiac myocytes, causing cardio\u00b7myopathy. Lapatinib (\u201cluh-PAH-tuh-nib\u201d) is a dual tyrosine kinase inhibitor used to treat this disease. One drug used to treat this disease is conjugated to the cytotoxic agent D-M-1 to form Kadcyla (\u201ccad-SIGH-luh\u201d). The Gail model provides a 5-year and lifetime probability of developing this condition. A symptom of this disease is skin textured like an orange rind, or (*) peau d\u2019orange. Trastuzumab (\u201ctraz-TOO-zoo-mab\u201d) is used to treat this disease, which is classified by the presence of HER\u00b72, estrogen receptor, and progesterone receptor. Mutations in BRCA (\u201cBRACK-uh\u201d) 1 and 2 can increase susceptibility to this disease. For 10 points, name this type of cancer detected by a mammogram.", "answer": "breast cancer [prompt on cancer]", "subcategory": "Biology", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "Trujillo-Gomez, Klypin, et al 2011 used this technique to produce a generalization including both the Tully-Fisher and Faber-Jackson relations. This technique was developed by Kravtsov et al 2004 in order to model S\u00b7D\u00b7S\u00b7S correlation functions. Extending this technique to satellite galaxies led to the discovery of the \u201ctoo big to fail\u201d problem. This technique is necessary because of the increase in computation complexity when including sub-grid baryonic physics in simulations. It can be graphically represented by tracing from the x-axis of one graph in mass up to the point on a number density function curve, then tracing that same number density over to a luminosity function curve to find a luminosity. For 15 points name this technique which assigns galaxies of an observed luminosity function to dark matter halos from an n-body simulation. ", "answer": "halo abundance matching [prompt on partial answer]", "subcategory": "Astronomy", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "When only a half-filled one of these states is occupied, composite fermions consisting of an electron and two flux quanta form the basis of a mean field theory of Fermi liquids developed by Halperin, Lee, and Read. Assuming the vector potential is equal to negative one-half of r cross B, the eigenfunction of the lowest of these states is the exponential of negative r squared over four times the magnetic length squared. The periodicity of the energy of these states is measured as oscillations in the magnetic moment with strong applied field in an effect used to map Fermi surfaces, called the (*) de Haas-van Alphen effect. Fermion doubling is absent in a model developed by Haldane that explains the quantum Hall effect as a result of T-symmetry breaking without the formation of these states. These states are analogous to the harmonic oscillator where omega is the cyclotron frequency. For 10 points, what are these quantized orbitals of electrons named for a Soviet physicist?", "answer": "Landau levels [accept Landau quantization]", "subcategory": "Physics", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "A group at Rice excited impurities in a Bose gas to create polarons named for this scientist. A bound pair of H-plus and H-minus forms a \u201cheavy\u201d state named for this scientist. A quantity named for this scientist times 2\u00b7h\u00b7c gives the Hartree energy. When the reduced mass is not being used for calculations, a quantity named for this scientist is typically written with an infinity subscript. His namesake correction subtracts \u201cdelta\u201d from the principal quantum number to account for (*) screening. The constant named for this man has units of inverse length and multiplies a term equal to [read slowly] \u201cquantity one over n-sub-1 squared minus quantity one over n-sub-2 squared,\u201d where n-sub-1 and n-sub-2 are principal quantum numbers. This man generalized a formula developed by Johann Balmer to apply to all similar transitions in hydrogen atoms. For 10 points, what Swede\u2019s namesake formula calculates spectral line wavelengths?", "answer": "Johannes Rydberg", "subcategory": "Chemistry", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "Lloyd N. Trefethen observed that, although error analysis suggests it should be half as efficient, a quadrature method based on these functions converges just as fast as Gaussian quadrature for most integrands. These functions may be defined by the equation \u201cT sub n of the cosine of theta equals the cosine of n theta.\u201d In Clenshaw-Curtis quadrature, Runge\u2019s (\u201cRUN-guh\u2019z\u201d) phenomenon can be minimized when the integrand is approximated using an (*) interpolation scheme based on these functions. Frequency is inputted into one of these functions in the frequency response of a filter with a steeper roll-off than the Butterworth filter but with more ripples in the pass-band. The namesake of these functions also names the statement that no more than \u201cone over k squared\u201d of a distribution\u2019s values can be further than k sigma from the mean. For 10 points, name this sequence of orthogonal polynomials named for a Russian mathematician.", "answer": "Chebyshev polynomials", "subcategory": "Math", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "The action of this complex on liprin (\u201cLIP-rinn\u201d)-alpha in Drosophila (\u201cdruh-SOFF-ill-uh\u201d) regulates synapse size. One protein which inhibits this complex has a G\u00b7L\u00b7E\u00b7B\u00b7S sequence adjacent to a low-complexity region; that protein is named for not being inhibited by benzimidazole (\u201cben-zuh-MID-uh-zole\u201d) and is part of the M\u00b7C\u00b7C, which is inhibited by p\u00b731-comet. E\u00b7m\u00b7i\u00b71 serves as both an inhibitor and substrate of this complex. This complex contains a \u201cplatform\u201d, a \u201ccatalytic core\u201d, and an arc-lamp shaped T\u00b7P\u00b7R lobe which interacts with the C-terminal W\u00b7D\u00b740 motifs of c\u00b7d\u00b7h\u00b71 and c\u00b7d\u00b7c\u00b720. In vertebrates, the substrate of this complex lacks a (*) D-box motif, and instead contains a portion known as the KEN-box. This complex, which contains 19 subunits, uses its E\u00b73 ubiquitin ligase activity to degrade securin, leading to the release of separase, which cleaves cohesins. For 10 points, name this protein complex that drives the transition from metaphase to the phase after.", "answer": "anaphase promoting complex [or cyclosome or APC/C]", "subcategory": "Biology", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "A low-pass filter is used to remove the effects of \u201csatellites\u201d of this substance in the DISPEL experiment. Pee Dee Belemnite is used as a standard for a ratio in which this substance is the heavier species; that ratio named for this substance has a negative anomaly in mass extinctions. Coupling between individual atoms of this substance is detected using the INADEQUATE experiment. Dynamic nuclear polarization is used to hyper\u00b7polarize this substance for measuring the forward (*) metabolic rate. Distortionless enhancement by polarization transfer is used to decouple signals between hydrogen and this substance; those signals appear between 0 and 220p\u00b7p\u00b7m in one technique. It makes up about 1.1% of the abundance of its element. For 10 points, name this N\u00b7M\u00b7R-active isotope of atomic element number 6.", "answer": "13C [or carbon-13; or C13; prompt on carbon]", "subcategory": "Chemistry", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "The slope of these things is directly proportional to the relative geostrophic vorticity according to the Margules (\u201cmar-GOO-less\u201d) equation.  The conditions of vertical circulation required for the formation of these things are described by the Sawyer-Eliassen equation. Locations where these things overlap can be represented by trowal (\u201cTROW-ul\u201d) symbols. Parcel deformation processes contribute to the formation of these things if the axis of dilatation (\u201cdie-luh-TAY-shun\u201d) lies within 45 degrees of an (*) isentrope. Jacob Bjerknes (\u201cYAH-kob BYURK-nes\u201d) introduced the term for these formations, whose presence is indicated by kinks in isobars that represent pressure at zero geopotential meters. They aren\u2019t on phase diagrams, but \u201ctriple points\u201d can form when one of these formations occludes another. Two types of them are depicted using red lines with semicircles and blue lines with triangles. For 10 points, name these boundaries between air masses which come in \u201chot\u201d and \u201ccold\u201d types.", "answer": "weather fronts [accept surface fronts or hot fronts or cold fronts; accept frontogenesis or frontolysis; prompt on temperature gradients]", "subcategory": "Earth Science", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "DeVries and Taylor added a cutout procedure to these constructs, which improved their performance on CIFAR-10 (\u201csee-far ten\u201d). Girschik created one of these constructs that begins by analyzing region proposals; that is their \u201cFaster R-\u201d type. Increasing the dilation factor in one part of these constructs obviates the need for upsampling. The depth, stride, and padding are hyperparameters that characterize these constructs. These constructs often use max pooling for dimensionality reduction after creating a feature map using their (*) namesake operation, which can be visualized by moving a matrix stepwise over a larger matrix of pixels. These algorithms are inspired by the mammalian visual cortex, where individual neurons have receptive fields. For 10 points, name these deep learning algorithms that usually use cross-correlation instead of their namesake operation, which for functions f and g is symbolized f star g.", "answer": "convolutional neural networks [accept CNNs or ConvNet; accept SIANN or shift-invariant artificial neural network or space-invariant artificial neural network; prompt on partial answers, prompt on perceptron or multilayer perceptron or neocognitron]", "subcategory": "Computer Science", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "This operation is applied to an exponential generating function and then evaluated at one in Borel\u2019s integral summation method. If the result of this operation converges everywhere except for a pole at z = 1, then the input of this operation is asymptotic to a constant times e to the x, according to the Wiener-Ikehara theorem. Applying this operation to a step function yields a general Dirichlet (\u201cdeer-uh-CLAY\u201d) series. The moment generating function of a random variable is the result of applying the two-sided form of this operation to the (*) probability density function. Euler derived the integral representation for n factorial by taking the nth-order derivative of the identity \u201cthis operation applied to one equals the function one over s.\u201d This operation transforms differential equations with constant coefficients into polynomial equations. The kernel of this transform is the negative exponential \u201ce to the negative s t.\u201d For 10 points, give this integral transform that converts functions from the time domain to the s-domain, denoted with a script L.", "answer": "Laplace transform [accept just Laplace after \u201ctransform\u201d]", "subcategory": "Math", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "One protein found in this structure, S\u00b7e\u00b7h\u00b71, associates with a scaffolding unit called a Y complex. The anti-p\u00b762 antibodies in primary biliary (\u201cBILL-ee-air-ee\u201d) cirrhosis (\u201csir-OH-sis\u201d) target this structure. Mutations in both inner and outer components of this structure are linked to steroid-resistant nephropathy. The SAGA and T\u00b7REX-2 complexes aid in one process carried out by this structure. Alkylation of C\u00b7R\u00b7M\u00b71 by leptomycin (\u201clep-toh-MY-sin\u201d) B inhibits this structure\u2019s function. Conjugating I\u00b7B\u00b7B to a quantum dot is one method of studying this structure, which are also modelled using Frey and Gorlich's hydrogels. This structure contains several intrinsically-disordered (*) F\u00b7G repeats. The reduction-of-dimensionality, selective-phase, and virtual gating models apply to this structure, which contains an inner ring attached to a basket and an outer ring attached to filaments. This complex is assisted by the Ran-G\u00b7T\u00b7P cycle, import\u00b7ins, and export\u00b7ins.  Nup subunits make up, for 10 points, what complexes in the nuclear membrane?", "answer": "nuclear pore complex [accept NPC; prompt on nucleus, pore, nuclear envelope, nuclear membrane]", "subcategory": "Biology", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "In d dimensions, the size of these objects is set to two to the power of the floor function of d over 2. In dimensional regularization, one-loop calculations often use \u201ctrace technology\u201d to simplify expressions containing these objects. The product of these objects and \u201cA sub mu,\u201d a covariant vector, is reduced to one symbol in Feynman (\u201cFINE-mun\u201d) slash notation. The anti\u00b7commutator of two of them equals 2 times the metric times the identity, a relation which generates a Clifford algebra. The (*) fifth of these entities, which in the chiral (\"KYE-rull\") basis is diagonal, can be found by multiplying i times the product of the other four of them. In covariant form, i times h-bar times one of these entities times d sub mu of phi (\u201cfye\u201d), all minus m c phi equals zero. For 10 points, name these matrices that appear in a relativistic wave equation describing spin one-half particles, named for a British physicist.", "answer": "Dirac matrices [or gamma matrices; accept matrix instead of matrices; do NOT accept \u201cspinor\u201d or \u201cDirac spinor\u201d, as those are different]", "subcategory": "Physics", "category": "Science"}]}